Finding Aid for the Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities Records of Facilities at 401 Wilshire, 1980-1994, and undated IA20015
Institutional Records and Archives
- Architectural records, 1980-1984; 1991,; undated; Series II.; 19 Linear Feet (2 boxes, 13 flat files, 2 oversize boxes, 4 oversize architectural roll boxes)
  - Batey and Mack, 1980-1990; Series II.A.; 28 Linear Feet (1 box, 6 flat files, 2 oversized boxes)
    - Blueline/architectural drawings:
      - Utilities plans:
        - Sheet #: A4.6, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Power and Telephone Layout, September 22, 1984 (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-3A)
        - Sheet #: A7.6, Sheet Title: Seventh Floor Power and Telephone Layout, November 13, 1984 (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-2B)
          [2nd copy dated September 22, 1984 in 1986.IA.21-Flat file 3A
      - Elevations:
        - Sheet #: 4.7, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Elevations, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-2C)
          [2nd copy in 1986.IA.21-Flat file 3B.]
        - Sheet #: 4.7, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Elevations, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-3B)
        - Sheet #: A7.8, Sheet Title: Seventh Floor Interior Elevations, September 22, 1984 (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-3A)
        - Sheet #: 7.9A, Sheet Title: Seventh Floor Interior Elevations, September 22, 1984 (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-3A)
        - Sheet Title: Seventh Floor West Elevation Work Area, September 23, 1984 (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-3B)
        - Sheet Title: Seventh Floor Elevation Study Rooms, September 20, 1984 (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-3B)
        - Sheet #: 7.7, Sheet Title: Seventh Floor Interior Elevations, September 22, 1984 (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-3B)
        - Sheet #: 7.8, Sheet Title: Seventh Floor Elevations, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.21-3B)
    - Architectural model of corridor, 401 Wilshire Blvd., undated (Box 1986.IA.21-7)
    - Architectural model of corridor, 401 Wilshire Blvd., undated (Box 1986.IA.21-8)
  - Neptune and Thomas Associates, 1980-1984; Series II.B.; 31.5 Linear Feet (1 box, 7 flat files, 2 oversize architectural roll boxes)
    These records are intellectually arranged by type of record, and by floor, where possible.
    Records consist of blue line prints and a report, 1980-1984, created by Neptune and Thomas Associates, for the renovation of the J. Paul Getty Center for the History of Art and Humanities, J. Paul Getty Trust, in Santa Monica. It is unclear whether these plans ever went beyond the draft stage, as they predate the Batey and Mack plans. The majority of the blueprints are titled "Santa Monica Research Facility." One set of the blueprints is labeled "County of Los Angeles, Department of Health Services Copy."
    The role of Neptune and Thomas Associates in the remodel of 401 Wilshire Blvd. remains unclear. These plans date predominantly from early 1983, predating those of Batey and Mack (late 1984).
    - First Federal Square Tenant Design Package, 1981; 1983 (Box 1986.IA.20-7, Folder 1)
      [Includes hand-written note to Tim from Howard re: enlargement of drawings.]
    - Santa Monica Research Facility Details, January 17, 1983; [File 1 of 2] (Box 1986.IA.20-7, Folder 2)
    - Santa Monica Research Facility Details, January 17, 1983; [File 2 of 2] (Box 1986.IA.20-7, Folder 3)
    - Blueline prints, Set 1:
      - Floor plans:
        - Sheet #: M-8, Sheet Title: Plaza Level Floor Plan, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
          [Photocopy]
        - Sheet #: M-9, Sheet Title: Mezzanine Level Floor Plan, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-10, Sheet Title: Second Floor Plan, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: K-1, Sheet Title: Floor Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: SK-1, Sheet Title: Second Floor Reflected Ceiling Plan [Revised Ceiling Grid Layout], August 10, 1980; [2 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-1, Sheet Title: General Notes and Symbols, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-1, Sheet Title: Title Sheet, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: M-11, Sheet Title: Third Floor Plan, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-12, Sheet Title: Typical Floor Plan 4th Thru 12th, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-13, Sheet Title: Typical Core 4th Thru 12th, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: A-9, Sheet Title: 4th thru 12th Floor Plans [Revisions], March 10, 1980-July 9, 1981 (Box 1986.IA.20-12)
        - Sheet #: 4026-15-R, Sheet Title: 4th Thru 12th Floor Duct Loops [Air Conditioning], November 21, 1980; [2 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-2, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Mechanical Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-2, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-8, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Reflected Ceiling Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-5, Sheet Title: Parking Level 4 Plan and Details [Revisions], March 10, 1980-February 24, 1981 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: A-3, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-9, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Reflected Ceiling Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: M-3, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Mechanical Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-4, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-10, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Reflected Ceiling Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-14, Sheet Title: Stair, Dumbwaiter and Enlarged Plans, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: M-4, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Mechanical Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: M-5, Sheet Title: First Parking Level Ventilation Plan, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-6, Sheet Title: Core Plans and Details Parking Levels 1 and 4, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-7, Sheet Title: Garage Exhaust Fan Rooms, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-14, Sheet Title: Partial Roof and Mechanical Penthouse Plan, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-15, Sheet Title: Roof Plan, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-16, Sheet Title: Details, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
      - Furniture plans:
        - Sheet #: A-5, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Furniture Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet Title: Room Designations Floor 4, October 4, 1982 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet Title: Room Designations Floor 4, November 11, 1982 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Offices Furniture Plan, undated; [4 Copies] (Roll 1986.IA.20-Roll 13)
        - Sheet #: A-6, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Furniture Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet Title: Library Shelving Floor 5, November 11, 1982 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet Title: Photo Archives Area Floor 5, October 4, 1982 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet Title: Photo Archives Shelving Fifth Floor, October 18, 1982 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Offices Furniture Plan, undated; [4 Copies] (Box 1986.IA.20-14)
        - Sheet #: A-7, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Furniture Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet Title: Shelving Units Floor 6, October 21, 1982 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet Title: Library Stack Area, Floor 6, October 4, 1982 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet Title: Inter-Office Partition Floor 6, August 9, 1984 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet Title: Library Stack Area Sixth Floor, October 18, 1982 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Offices Furniture Plan, undated; [3 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet Title: 10th Floor Offices, May 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet Title: 10th Floor Offices Furniture Plan, June 6, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
      - Utilities plans:
        - Sheet #: A-11, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Utility Layout Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: M-2, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Mechanical Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: E-1, Sheet Title: Notes, Symbols and Fixture Schedule, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: E-2, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Lighting Plan and Panels, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: E-3, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Power and Telephone Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: E-4, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Signal Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-11, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Utility Layout Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: E-3, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Power and Telephone Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: P1, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Plumbing Plan, May 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet #: A-11, Sheet Title: Fourth Floor Utility Layout Plan, February 3, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet #: A-12, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Utility Layout Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: M-3, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Mechanical Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: E-5, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Lighting Plan and Panels, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: E-6, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Power and Telephone Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: E-7, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Signal Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-12, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Utility Layout Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: E-6, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Power and Telephone Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: A-12, Sheet Title: Fifth Floor Utility Layout Plan, February 3, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet #: A-13, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Utility Layout Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: M-4, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Mechanical Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: E-8, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Lighting Plan and Panels, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: E-9, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Power and Telephone Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: E-10, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Signal Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-13, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Utility Layout Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: K-2, Sheet Title: Plumbing and Electrical Rough-In Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: E-9, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Power and Telephone Plan, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
        - Sheet #: A-13, Sheet Title: Sixth Floor Utility Layout Plan, February 3, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet #: C15, Sheet Title: Doors at Elevator Lobbies, March 2, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
          [Photocopy.]
        - Sheet #: 1686, Sheet Title: Exhaust Replacement Air System, April 12, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
        - Sheet #: 1686, Sheet Title: Item 30 Ventilator, April 12, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet #: M-17, Sheet Title: Toilet Exhaust, Chilled and Hot Water, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-18, Sheet Title: Power Wiring Diagram, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: M-19, Sheet Title: Control Wiring Diagram, January 9, 1980 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
      - Elevations:
        - Sheet #: A-15, Sheet Title: Interior Elevations, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: A-16, Sheet Title: Interior Elevations, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
        - Sheet #: K-3, Sheet Title: Interior Elevations, January 17, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-1)
      - Safety and Security Plans:
        - Sheet #: 2500, Sheet Title: Hydro-Temp Moisture Detection System Floor 4, April 12, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: 2500A, Sheet Title: Graphic Annunciator Floor 4, May 9, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: PWL-1212, Sheet Title: Fire Device Layout Fourth Floor, April 20, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet #: TM-4, Sheet Title: Box Terminal Schedule Fourth Floor, May 11, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
        - Sheet #: SS-1, Sheet Title: Security Systems 4th Floor, February 21, 1983; [2 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: 2500, Sheet Title: Hydro-Temp Moisture Detection System Floor 5, April 12, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: 2500, Sheet Title: Single Line Electrical Floor 5, April 27, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: 2500B, Sheet Title: Graphic Annunciator Floor 5, May 9, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: SS-2, Sheet Title: Security Systems 5th Floor, February 21, 1983; [2 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: SS-4, Sheet Title: Security Systems Typical Details - Installation, Fifth Floor Furniture Plan, February 8, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: 2500, Sheet Title: Hydro-Temp Moisture Detection System Floor 6, April 12, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: 2500, Sheet Title: Halon 1301 Fire Suppression System Floor 6, December 12, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: 2500, Sheet Title: Halon 1301 Fire Suppression System Floor 6 part II, December 12, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: SS-3, Sheet Title: Security Systems 6th Floor, February 21, 1983; [2 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-10)
        - Sheet #: 2500, Sheet Title: Halon 1301 Fire Suppression System, December 13, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: 2500C, Sheet Title: Graphic Annunciator Floor 6, May 9, 1983; [5 Copies] (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-4)
        - Sheet #: M-15, Sheet Title: Control Diagrams, January 9, 1980 (Box 1986.IA.20-12)
          [Labeled "First Federal Square."]
        - Sheet #: 1686, Sheet Title: Exhaust Replacement Air System, April 12, 1983 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
    - Blueline prints, Set 2 (partial duplicate of Set 1):
      - Sheet #s: A-1, A-2, A-3, A-4, A-5, A-6, A-7, A-8, A-9, A-10, A-14, A-15, A-16, K-1, K-2, K-3, M-1, E-1, E-2, E-3, E-4, E-5, E-7, E-8, E-10 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-2)
      - Sheet #s: A-11, A-12, A-13 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-5)
      - Sheet #s: E-3, E-6, E-9 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-6)
    - Blueline prints, Set 3, County of Los Angeles, Department of Health Services Copy (partial duplicate of Set 1):
      - Sheet #s: A-1, A-2, A-3, A-4, A-5, A-6, A-7, A-8, A-9, A-10, A-11, A-12, A-13, A-14, A-15, A-16, K-1, K-2, K-3, M-1, M-2, M-3, M-4, E-1, E-2, E-3, E-4, E-5, E-6, E-7, E-8, E-9, E-10 (Flatfile 1986.IA.20-3)
  - Richard Meier and Associates, Series II.C.; 2 Linear Feet (2 oversize architectural roll boxes)
    These records are arranged by type of plan.
    Records consist of blueline prints, 1991, created by the architectural firm of Richard Meier and Associates for the J. Paul Getty Center for the History of Art and Humanities, J. Paul Getty Trust. The blueprints were created for floors 8 and 9 of 401 Wilshire Blvd., the administrative offices of the GCHAH. The GCHAH began occupancy of these two additional floors in 1991. The dates listed are the permit dates; each blueprint is marked with the bid, revision and permit dates.
    - Set 1:
      - Sheet #: TA1.1, Sheet Title: Level 8 Plan, June 14, 1991 (Box 2003.IA.01-1)
      - Sheet #: TA1.2, Sheet Title: Level 9 Plan, June 14, 1991 (Box 2003.IA.01-1)
      - Sheet #: TA5.1, Sheet Title: Level 8 Elevations, June 14, 1991 (Box 2003.IA.01-1)
      - Sheet #: TA5.2, Sheet Title: Level 8 Elevations, June 14, 1991 (Box 2003.IA.01-1)
      - Sheet #: TA5.4, Sheet Title: Level 9 Elevations, June 14, 1991 (Box 2003.IA.01-1)
      - Sheet #: TA5.5, Sheet Title: Level 9 Elevations, June 14, 1991 (Box 2003.IA.01-1)
      - Sheet #: TA7.1, Sheet Title: Level 8 Millwork Plan, June 14, 1991 (Box 2003.IA.01-1)
      - Sheet #: TA7.2, Sheet Title: Level 9 Millwork Plan, June 14, 1991 (Box 2003.IA.01-1)
    - Set 2 (exact duplicate of Set 1) (Box 2003.IA.1-2)